interwetten.gr 2011-07-04

# Interwetten.com

##  PRIVACY POLICY

​  
Protecting our players’/customers’ privacy is important to Interwetten. All gaming companies, i.e. Interwetten Malta Ltd, Interwetten Gaming Ltd and Interwetten Entertainment Ltd, as well as Eurotrade International Ltd, the operator of [www.iwfriends.com](http://www.iwfriends.com/), have been notified under the Data Protection Act (Chapter 440 of the Laws of Malta) to the Office of the Commissioner for Data Protection in Malta. We strive to keep your personal information protected. Please take a moment to read the following policy to learn how we handle your personal information, as your use of our services will indicate your acceptance of its content. 

In general, any customer may open our website and move around on our webpage without transmitting information or data.

 Each player/customer, however wishing to use our services must open an account with Interwetten Malta Ltd. in order to be able to utilise any product offered by Interwetten (sports- betting, casino, skill games).  Whenever a player/customer strikes a bet or takes part in a game, s/he accepts the validity and applicability of this Privacy Policy, the [General Terms and Conditions](https://www.interwetten.com/Common/CMS/CMS.aspx?type=5&tid=Terms%20and%20conditions%20of%20business&ln=TermsAndConditionsCategory|TermsAndConditions), the relevant rules (sportsbook, casino or skill games) as well as the applicable terms for promotions, special offers and bonuses, as amended from time to time.

  **Required Personal Data**  
In order to use the services of Interwetten, the customer has to fill in the online registration form.

  The following are the minimum required personal data:  
\- First name and Last name  
\- Complete address  
\- Date of Birth  
\- A verifiable email address  
\- Sex  
\- Proof of age   
Interwetten may request, at any given time and in line with the applicable laws and regulations, that the player/customer submits certain documents as proof of identity for a security identity check. Interwetten reserves the right to retain any winnings until the requested documents are submitted. You may be asked to submit one or more of the following documents:

 a) a copy of a valid ID issued by the competent authority of a recognised state/country, e.g. passport, personal identity card, driver’s license. In order to verify the player’s/customer’s identity we may also ask you for a utility bill (e.g. for gas, electricity) or a lease contract;

 b)  a copy of each credit card (front and back) used for making deposits to the Interwetten account of the player/customer as well as a copy of the credit card statements.

c) a copy of bank vouchers, account statements e.g. of a Moneybookers Account, etc.  
If the customer whishes to deposit funds into the Interwetten account by using a credit card, the customer has to transmit the following personal data additionally:

 \- Name and surname of cardholder   
\- Name of credit card company   
\- Credit card number   
\- Expiry date of credit card & CVC-code

  In order to enable us, to transfer winnings into the customer´s (player´s) bank account, the following personal data is needed in addition:  
\- Name and surname of account holder   
\- Name of bank   
\- IBAN   
\- SWIFT-code 

 In order to assure, that only the customer receives the amount of payout, the customer has to send us, upon our request, a copy of an official document which includes a photograph of the customer (e.g. passport, driving license, identity document), either by fax or as scan by e-mail before the first payout of winnings is allowed. Interwetten reserves the right to retain any winnings until the required documents are submitted. 

 By supplying us with your information you confirm that you do not consider use of your information in accordance with this privacy policy to be a breach of your rights under the Data Protection Act (Chapter 440 under the Laws of Malta). Herewith the player/customer explicitly grants permission to Interwetten to process, use and disclose to a third party the transmitted data in accordance with this privacy policy.  
We encourage you to contact us at any time and remind you of your right to opt out from receiving any promotional or marketing material from us as outlined in our genereal [Terms and Conditions](https://www.interwetten.com/Common/CMS/CMS.aspx?type=5&tid=Terms%20and%20conditions%20of%20business&ln=TermsAndConditionsCategory|TermsAndConditions).

On the other hand any and all information provided to us by the player/customer must be correct and complete. The player/customer undertakes to notify us without any delay in the event that any information provided to us becomes incorrect or incomplete. We reserve the right to cancel any bets as well as winnings, block betting accounts, exclude the customer/player from participating in other games and retain payments to the player/customer if any information given to us by the player/customer turns out to be incorrect or incomplete. The player/customer is liable for any damage and costs arising out of false or misleading information. If any deliberately false or misleading information is furnished, any and all transactions on the betting account shall be declared invalid.

   **No Participation of Underage Persons**

 Interwetten does not allow underage persons (under the age of 18) to participate in sports betting and/or games of chance.   
That is why Interwetten requests that players/customers confirm that they are of legal age and give their date of birth upon registration. Interwetten reserves the right to verify any player’s/customer’s statement of age and to exclude players/customers from its services, if there are any doubts regarding the attainment of the minimum age required. 

 Any customer using our services, who is identified as underage, shall have all his winnings forfeited and his account shall be blocked immediately. In principal, minors are not allowed to use any of our products, may it be the sportsbook or any other games of chance.

   **Use of personal data**

 When handling the information pertaining to the player/customer, Interwetten will observe the relevant statutory data protection provisions. All data will be processed in an automated manner. According to this privacy policy, the disclosure of data will always be subject to the written approval of the player/customer unless such disclosure occurs vis-á-vis companies being part of the Interwetten-Group, such as subsidiaries of Interwetten Holding Ltd., its shareholders and their respective subsidiaries, or unless such disclosure is required vis-á-vis service providers that sustain our gaming products or provide ancillary services (such as supporting or marketing services), or unless  such disclosure is imperative under the legal provisions as applicable from time to time, or required in order to pursue any claims of Interwetten in connection with sports bets, or if it is necessary or appropriate to scrutinize circumstances indicating fraudulent behavior or activity. 

Upon the slightest indication of transactions and/or activities indicating potential criminal activities we shall report to the relevant authorities (e.g. police, sporting associations, private associations focused on the investigation of criminal or fraudulent activities in relation to sports betting and/or games of chance). In this context, personal data may also be transferred to the European Sports Security Asscociation (ESSA) and sports federations in the framework of an early warning system. The player/customer gives his/her unambiguous consent to the processing of his/her personal data as outlined above when accepting the Interwetten Privacy Policy. 

Acceptance of our Privacy Policy authorizes us to conduct such security reviews which may include ordering of credit reports or verification of the information supplied by you against third party databases. For this purpose, Interwetten furthermore reserves the right to record telephone calls with customers in order to pass on to third parties for the purpose of prosecution.

Our commitment to the protection of your personal data notwithstanding, Interwetten reserves the right to make gaming data (e.g. achieved results in our gaming products) and the first name as well as the country of residence of the respective user public on the Interwetten site.

If the customer/player closes the Interwetten account, the personal data saved in our system will be kept saved for a period of seven years, commencing from the date of the closure of the Interwetten account. After expiration of this period of seven years, the personal data will be deleted upon the customer's (player's) request.

The transfer of data for online gaming requires the use of codes (username and password) chosen by the player/customer himself/herself. Username and passwords choosen by the player/customer shall. be robust enough and kept secret. Interwetten will not be liable for any abuse of the account through the use of the player’s/customer’s username and password by third parties. We expressly state that the username and password must be kept secret and confidential by the player/customer as all transactions via the account for which the username and password must be entered will be for the account of the player/customer.

  The username and password should never be disclosed to third parties by the player/customer. It is the player’s/customer’s sole responsibility to keep his/her username and password secure. The player/customer cannot make any claims whatsoever from a third party unlawfully placing bets by using his/her password and username.

Interwetten operates on the basis of the assumption that each person logging into the system with the correct combination of username and password actually is the lawful account holder/player/customer. It is in particular not permissible to make any transactions for the account of others, on the Interwetten accounts of third parties, by forming syndicates of players or in conspiracy with third parties. Interwetten reserves the right to close Interwetten accounts, cancel transactions and retain the payment of funds if the account holder has made his/her account available to third parties, makes transactions on behalf of or in the name of third parties, in conjunction with third parties, in groups/syndicates of players, or in violation of other provisions of the General Terms and Conditions or the applicable Rules. 

  **Profile**

We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our customers (players). A profile is stored information that we keep on individual customers (players) users that detail their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the customers´ personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the customer (player). This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our Web site and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We do not share your profile with any other third parties outside the Interwetten Group. 

   **Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the customer´s computer tied to information about the customer. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the customer´s hard drive for an extended period of time. 

   **Log Files**

Interwetten uses log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to enable our Web-based service. 

   **Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**

Some of our third party advertising companies use a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that helps us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between a cookie and a clear gifs is that clear gifs are invisible on the page. Clear gifs are not tied to users' personally identifiable information. Clear Gifs together with cookies can be used to identify the previous online behavior of the user of the respective computer. Such information would then be made available to an advertising company.

  Technical dimension within the Privacy Policy – Security  
We trace and record on our technical systems the IP address of our customers and use it in order to provide you with a better technical service and to prevent fraudulent activities. All data will be processed in an automated manner.

  Interwetten takes every reasonable precaution to protect customers´ information with physical, managerial and electronic procedures. In particular, information is encrypted when our registration/order form asks customers to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number).   
While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also undertake anything reasonable to protect customer-information off-line. 

  All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only authorized Interwetten employees, or employees of subcontracted service companies with identical data protection obligations, are granted access to personally identifiable information. We perform checks on all our employees to ensure that none of them has a criminal record. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every year and whenever a , new policy is added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users' information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment. 

  **Data Encryption**

To protect your personal data during communication with your web browser, the company uses secure and tested encryption technology from Thawte. Online transactions continue to be protected by the extremely reliable security system of a worldwide-accredited partner.

   **Other Technical Security Measures**

To prevent the illegal manipulation through a third person, the IP-Address of the logged-on computer will be requested and saved. In addition, all your data is protected from unauthorized access by a so-called firewall and intrusion prevention systems– a computer that is fitted with complex security technology specifically designed to shield the company's network from the internet. 

  Disclaimer: No liability for unintentional release of personal data

a.  Interwetten is committed to ensuring that its customers are protected in the best possible way by means of up to date security levels, however Interwetten shall take no responsibility whatsoever for events beyond its control inclusive of but not limited to acts of God or natural disasters, including also power cuts and strikes. 

  b. Interwetten will under no circumstances be liable for any damage caused by any incorrect, delayed, manipulated/rigged or abusive transfer of data via the internet.

  c. We are convinced, that our customers understand the ever-changing nature of our business due to continuous technological novelties and although we take all reasonable preventive measures to ensure the protection and privacy of your personal data at all times, we cannot take any responsibility that the performance of our services will be free from error. Should any such error have an effect or consequence relating to the privacy of your personal data we shall not be liable in any manner whatsoever in damages or otherwise. 

 Accordingly, we encourage you to take every precaution to protect your personal data yourself whenever you are on the internet.

**Change of personal data**

 After logging in, customers (players) may change their personal data at any time (with the exception of the surname, first name, country, date of birth as well as their login name and nicknames) in the „personal settings“ section of the Interwetten homepage, [www.interwetten.com](http://www.interwetten.com/). If any personal data becomes incorrect, the customer (player) is obliged to notify such changes without any delay.

  **Right of access  
**  
Under the Data Protection Act (Chapter 440 of the Laws of Malta), customers/players have a right of access to their personal data processed by Interwetten, including a right of rectification, erasure or blocking of data the processing of which does not comply with the Data Protection Act.

 **Further questions**

 If customers (players) have any questions about this privacy policy or the security of personal data transmitted to us, please send an email to [service@interwetten.com](mailto:service@interwetten.com).

 This privacy policy is set forth in several different languages. In the event of a discrepancy or dispute as to the meaning of a word or matters of interpretation, this English text is to prevail over all others.

The Interwetten privacy policy is subject to change at any time. We encourage you to review the privacy policy regularily for any changes. 

Version 3.42 - 01.12.2010

References:  
Data protection Act 2001 of the Laws of Malta  
Legal Notice 16 of the Laws of Malta

Top of page
